

HAMMAD ANSARI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

CONTACT INFORMATION

hammadansari17egmail.com

(+91) 9820129695



I'm an Engineer. I have worked on several different live projects during my graduation and internships. I am willing to make a difference by adapting new things quickly and sharing my knowledge to make this world a

18/27, L.I.G Colony, Kurla West, Mumbai - 400070



H4MM4D



Fruxc



<u>Fruxc</u>

WORK HISTORY

Tech Intern

IMPACTGURU VENTURES
MAY 2019 TO JULY 2019

- Database, Code, and Query Optimization.
- Achieved developing a good number of new features, such as implementing Cropper JS.
- Research and development SQL database to NoSQL, such as ElasticSearch to perform much faster search operations.

impactguru.com

Tech Intern

ZEAL ENTERPRISE

DEC 2018 TO JAN 2019

- Made an end to end business application using Zoho Creator.
- Made an e-Commerce Website to take their business offline business online using Woocommerce and Wix.

printaro.co.in

TECHNICAL SKILLS (BASICS)

Programming/Scripting Languages:

JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, C++, PYTHON

Framework:

LARAVEL, IONIC

• Front-End:

REACT JS

Back-End:

NODE JS, PHP, C#

Database Management:

ORACLE, MONGODB

Tools:

GIT, FIGMA, DOCKER

• Operating System:

LINUX (UBUNTU, REDHAT), WINDOWS 10

• Cloud Platform:

GOOGLE CLOUD PLATFORM

FORMAL EDUCATION

Sardar Patel Institute of Technology

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS, AUTONOMOUS, 2018 - 2021 EXPECTED

- Maintained a 7.9+ GPA.
- Overall a good performer.

Akbar Peerbhoy College of Commerce and Economics

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE FOCUSED IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, MUMBAI UNIVERSITY, 2015 - 2018

- Awarded as First Ranker Graduation.
- Awarded as Student of the year.
- Maintained a percentage of 80+.

HOBBIES

- Gym daily.
- Cycling on weekends.
- Going out for trekking with friends.

PROJECTS

better place. I'd love to work as a DevOps Engineer or a Full Stack Engineer.

Al News Application

REACTJS, ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (ALAN AI), REST API

- The application works on your voice command.
- The application searches any terms for you and brings the result on your screen and reads it out for you.
- You can search for news by country, terms, categories, sources, and many more. Want to try? <u>Click Here</u>

Movie Recommendation System

JAVA

- The system calculates recommendations based on weighted average ratings of the users who are close to you.
- Displays recommended movies for a given user on a webpage.

Restaurant Application

REACTJS || REACT NATIVE, MONGO, NODE JS

- An admin panel and user panel and have basic functionalities of creating dishes, leaders, and promotions for the website.
- A particular user can comment on the dish.

Society Application

LARAVEL, MYSQL, DOCKER

- Society Management System for Raunak Society with admin panel and user panel and have basic functionalities of creating members, maintenance, and changing staff members.
- It generates pdf of maintenance for the society members automatically.

Zeal Application (2018)

ZOHO CREATOR, DELUGE SCRIPT

- An end-to-end business application.
- The application consists of a sales dashboard, order request, assigned designers, production, and till the status of payment has been done.
- The application does include a regular attendance system for employees.

OTHER

- Any Task (Ionic React, Firebase)
- Steganography JS, Filter Fun (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)
- Coronavirus Tracker Live (ReactJS)

GitHub Profile

CERTIFICATIONS

- Full-Stack Web Development with React by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
- Java Programming and Software Engineering Fundamentals by Duke University
- Modern JavaScript: ES6 Basics
- Algorithms Specialization by Stanford University (On-Going)
- Continuous Delivery & DevOps by University of Virginia (On-Going)
- Rest API Intermediate on HackerRank.

Coursera Profile

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Volunteer/Tutor

JULY 2019

Volunteer/Tutor for TFI on weekends (Mathematics and Sports)

Mentor of First Year Students

2019-2020 SEM-I

Basics of Laravel on project Social Application.